Oladayo Ogundipe

Based in Los Angeles, CA

Email: <u>oladayogn@gmail.com</u>

Phone: 617-980-3213

Summary: Goal oriented software engineer open to full-time positions or contract roles. I have experience working on teams using Agile Scrum methodology using project management software like Trello

Github: http://github.com/itsdayo I try to contribute and learn new technologies by doing open source.

Relevant Side Projects:

Web Maker: https://app-maker-do.herokuapp.com, A angular web app that uses Angular, Express, Node.js, and Mongodb. The app allows users to save data as website, pages and widgets and uploads photos to Amazon S3. The database is NoSQL/MongoDB. The full stack was developed, designed and deployed by one developer.

React Native Calculator: https://github.com/itsdayo/ReactNativeCalculator, this project showcases my front-end architect skills along with expertise using a react hooks. It uses modern best practices such as React and styled-components.

Yugioh: https://github.com/itsdayo/Yugioh, this project was done using React, Redux, C# and SQL. It allows users to communicate to an API to display all yugioh cards for viewing purposes. Also, battle opponents using an algorithm I created.

Portfolio: Other highlighted projects can be found https://do-portfolio.netlify.app

Work Experience:

CarSwoop – Aug 2019 – Nov 2019 Junior Software Engineer (Santa Monica, CA)

- Build upon an application and web platform using React for the frontend and Nodejs/firebase for the backend.
- Designed a full stack application with technologies such as CSS, Jquery, Bootstrap and HTML
- Utilized MapKit JS to display mapping in real-time for the location of drivers in the system.

Next Round – Apr 2019 - Aug 2019 Full Stack Developer (Culver City, LA)

- By using React, global state Redux, C# and MySQL, I designed, developed, and build software code to provide new functionality
- Used object-oriented design principles to develop a web application using the efficient, modular .Net ecosystem.
- Implemented back-end service solutions using C# and Managed Microsoft SQL server
- Implemented a feature for users to view the locations of fields and venues and associated map route using the Google Maps API
- Created search tools and algorithms that SQL schemas can discover relationships and keywords for searched queries

MSIMBO Boot Camp Apr 2017-Aug 2017 Full stack developer (Boston MA)

- Developed next generation technologies and focused on API development
- Troubleshoot and debug dynamic SPA using MEAN stack
- Utilized AWS lambda to process images when its uploaded by adding images into a S3 bucket

• Managing databases using MongoDB

National Science Foundation (CSUMS) Summer 2013 Student Researcher (North Dartmouth MA)

- Developed highly interactive games called Nim and Mastermind using JavaScript, HTML5, Jquery, and CSS3.
- Completing research tasks that involved test automation, web development and game design.
- Implemented code that contributed to the development of a mathematical game using strategic computation.

Education

- High School: John D O'Bryant Class of 2011
- College: University of Massachusetts Dartmouth Bachelor of Science Mathematics Graduated May 2016

Technical Expertise:

Willing to learn new technologies not listed and prefer companies that provide confidence to developers to work across the stack

- Computer Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Python, SQL
- Backend Nodejs, C#/.Net, Express, Postgres, MongoDB, Wordpress
- Frontend: React, AngularJS, Sass, HTML5, CSS3, ES6, Redux, JQuery, Advanced Rest Client, Bootstrap 4.0
- Mobile: React Native,
- Versioning: Git, Github, Heroku, Stash
- Build tools: webpack, Babel,